thanard.kurutach@berkeley.edu

University of California, Berkeley, Berkeley, CA

2451 LeConte Ave, Berkeley CA, 94709

2016 - present

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am interested in using artificial intelligence to better human lives, and make better decisions. My current research goal is to develop algorithms that enable agents to efficiently solve complex decision-making problems using learning and planning.

## **EDUCATION**

Candidate for Ph.D. in Computer Science Research Adivsors: Pieter Abbeel, Stuart Russell	4.0/4.0
Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA Candidate for B.S. in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Candidate for B.S. in Mathematics	$2012 - 2016 \ 4.9/5.0 \ 5.0/5.0$
Awards and Honours	
UC Berkeley EECS Department Fellowship	2016
${\bf Provost's~Graduate~Excellence~Fellowship}~(decline)$	2016 - 2020
Lincoln Laboratory Undergraduate Research and Innovation Scholar	2015
Royal Thai Scholar	2011 - 2016
Round 2 Qualifier, Google Code Jam	2013
Gold Medal, 52nd International Mathematical Olympiad (IMO)	2011
Gold Medal, Asian Pacific Mathematics Olympiad (APMO)	2011
Silver Medal, 51st International Mathematical Olympiad (IMO)	2010
Silver Medal, 50th International Mathematical Olympiad (IMO)	2009

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Michael Laskin\*, Scott Emmons\*, Ajay Jain\*, **Thanard Kurutach**, Pieter Abbeel, Deepak Pathak. "Sparse Graphical Memory for Robust Planning" *Proceedings of Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)*, 2020.

Younggyo Seo\*, Kimin Lee\*, Ignasi Clavera, **Thanard Kurutach**, Jinwoo Shin, Pieter Abbeel. "Trajectory-wise Multiple Choice Learning for Dynamics Generalization in Reinforcement Learning." *Proceedings of Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)*, 2020.

Thanard Kurutach\*, Kara Liu\*, Pieter Abbeel, Aviv Tamar. "Hallucinative Topological Memory for Zero-Shot Visual Planning." *Proceedings of the International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)*, 2020.

Yilin Wu\*, Wilson Yan\*, **Thanard Kurutach**, Lerrel Pinto, Pieter Abbeel. "Learning to Manipulate Deformable Objects without Demonstrations." *Proceedings of the Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)*, 2020.

Angelina Wang, **Thanard Kurutach**, Kara Liu, Pieter Abbeel, Aviv Tamar. "Learning Robotic Manipulation through Visual Planning and Acting." *Proceedings of the Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)*, 2019.

**Thanard Kurutach**\*, Aviv Tamar\*, Ge Yang, Stuart Russell, Pieter Abbeel. "Learning Plannable Representation with Causal InfoGAN." *Proceedings of Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)*, 2018.

**Thanard Kurutach**, Ignasi Clavera, Yan Duan, Aviv Tamar, Pieter Abbeel. "Model Ensemble Trust Region Policy Optimization." *Proceedings of the International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR)*, 2018.

Lawson Wong, **Thanard Kurutach**, Leslie Kaelbling, Tomás Lozano-Peréz. "Object-based World Modeling in Semi-Static Environments with Dependent Dirichlet-Process Mixtures." *Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)*, 2016.

#### PREPRINTS

Michael Laskin, **Thanard Kurutach**, Pieter Abbeel. "Discrete Representation Learning for Goal-Conditioned Visual Reinforcement Learning" NeurIPS Workshop on Deep Reinforcement Learning, 2019.

**Thanard Kurutach**, Mohammad Babaeizadeh, Dumitru Erhan, Sergey Levine, Chelsea Finn. "Hierarchical Visual Model-based Reinforcement Learning" *ICLR Workshop on Beyond Tabula Rasa in Reinforcement Learning*, 2020.

**Thanard Kurutach**\*, Julia Peng\*, Yang Gao, Stuart Russell, Pieter Abbeel. "Discrete Predictive Representation for Long-horizon Planning" NeurIPS Workshop on Object Representations for Learning and Reasoning, 2020.

Tal Daniel, **Thanard Kurutach**, Aviv Tamar. "Deep Variational Semi-Siupervised Novelty Detection." In submission to AISTATS, 2021.

#### ORAL PRESENTATIONS

Learning Representation for Planning and Acting. BayLearn, Facebook. October 2018.

Learning Plannable Representation with Causal InfoGAN. ICML/IJCAI/AAMAS Workshop on Planning and Learning. July 2018.

#### RESEARCH AND INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Berkeley Artificial Intelligence Research (BAIR), Research Assistant	2016 – present
Google, Inc., Brain Team, Student Researcher	2019 - 2020
Google, Inc., Speech Team, Research Intern	2016
EnergySage, Inc., Data Scientist Intern	2016
Learning and Intelligent Systems Group, with Kaelbling, Lozano-Peréz	2014 - 2016
MIT CSAIL Machine Learning Group, with Stefanie Jegelka	2015 - 2015
National ICT Australia, Research Intern	2014
Harvard Microrobotics Laboratory, with Robert J. Wood	2013
Nanostructures and Computation Group, with Steven G. Johnson	2012 - 2013

## TEACHING EXPERIENCE

## **Invited Lectures**

 ${\it Lecture~AI~and~Neural~Network~Design} \\ {\it in~Leading~Trends~in~Humanities,~the~Sciences~and~Technology~program,~UC~Berkeley~Extension.} \\$ 

## Teaching Assistant

Berkeley CS188: Introduction to Artificial Intelligence	Fall 2018
MIT 6.036: Introduction to Machine Learning	Spring 2016
MIT 6.008: Introduction to Inference	Fall 2015
MIT 18.310: Principles of Applied Mathematics	Fall 2014
MIT 6.001: Introduction to EECS	Spring 2013

## MENTORING AND ADVISING

## Undergraduate students:

Julia Peng, UC Berkeley
Fenglu Hong, UC Berkeley
Yilin Wu, Shanghai Jiao Tong University
Wilson Yan, UC Berkeley
Angelina Wang, UC Berkeley
Kara Liu, UC Berkeley
Christine Tung, UC Berkeley

# Visiting Scholars:

Ge Yang, PhD student, University of Chicago Misha Laskin, PhD graduate, University of Chicago Yuto Fujii, Engineer, Komatsu Ltd Now at Facebook
Now MS student at Stanford
Becoming MS student at Stanford
Now PhD student at UC Berkeley
Now PhD student at Princeton
Becoming PhD student at Stanford
Now at Google

## PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

## Paper Reviewing:

Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2019, 2020 International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2021 International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2019, 2021 American Association for Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) 2020 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2019, 2020

## VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

## Youth Leader

2018 - present

Soka Gakkai International

I foster youth in my local community to engage in peace activities that focus on one-on-one encouragements and dialogue as a lasting foundation for creating a culture of peace.